Employment Collection, 1817-1991 (bulk 1920-1976)
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Employment collection
1817-1991
1920-1976
MS 456
67 boxes, 43 volumes (30.5 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Primarily printed materials and books, plus some unpublished writings, correspondence, photographs, and ephemera, pertaining to employment issues and specific occupations of women primarily in the U.S. and England. Topics include affirmative action, sex discrimination, labor organizing, child labor, immigrant workers, women in industry, jury duty, wartime work, Social Security, and protective legislation. Over eighty occupations represented include: law, academics, social work, sciences, domestic work, industrial labor, business, the armed services, government and politics, and philanthropy.
The Employment Collection is comprised primarily of printed materials and includes publications, pamphlets, periodicals, handbooks, statistics, bibliographies, biographies, reports, and newsletters pertaining to the employment of women. There are also unpublished writings and correspondence, photographs, and ephemera. The collection dates from 1817 to 1991, with the bulk dating from 1920 to 1976. Major topics include affirmative action, sex discrimination, labor organizing, married women, child labor, minority women, protective legislation, volunteer services, and specific occupations in relation to women. A section on the status of women in labor is arranged by country, primarily England and the U.S., then by states in the U.S.
There is general material related to women in over eighty different occupations, including a large amount on women in academic occupations, as well as women in the armed services, aviation, government and politics, law, science, social work, and philanthropy. There are also materials related to women domestic workers, immigrant workers, women in industry, jury duty, wartime work, Social Security, and day care. There is a substantial amount of information on women labor leaders and union members, primarily in the Women's Trade Union League, United Electrical Workers, and the Working Women's Protective Union. There are also numerous publications by the Women's Bureau of the United States Department of Labor. Other items of interest include a photographic collection entitled "Women at Work: Views and Visions from the Pioneer Valley, 1870-1945"; a board game from 1890, "Round the World with Nellie Bly"; interviews of Samuel Gompers and Jane Addams about Hull House conducted by Lucy Robbins Lang; a payroll ledger from Ashuelot, NH, circa 1870s; and posters from Geraldine Ferraro's vice-presidential campaign.
This collection is organized into fourteen series:
I. GENERAL
II. COUNTRIES
III. DOMESTIC SERVICE
IV. INDUSTRIAL RELATIONS
V. OCCUPATIONS
VI. ACADEMIC WOMEN
VII. COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES
VIII. ARMED SERVICES AND AVIATION
IX. GOVERNMENT AND POLITICS
X. LABOR LEADERS
XI. LAW
XII. SCIENCES
XIII. SOCIAL WORK AND PHILANTHROPY
XIV. TRADE UNIONS
OVERSIZE MATERIALS
BOOKS ON SHELF
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The collection is open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
Additions to the Collection
Periodic additions are expected and may not be reflected in this finding aid.
History of the Collection
Materials in this subject collection were either purchased or given to the Sophia Smith Collection by various donors.
Search Terms
United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America--History; United States. Women's Bureau. --Periodicals; Women's Trade Union League--History; Working Women's Protective Union (New York, N.Y.)-History; Industrial relations--United States--History; Sex discrimination in employment--United States--History; Social workers--United States--History; United States--Armed Forces--Women--History; Universities and colleges--United States--History; Women--Employment--History; Women--Economic conditions--History; Women college teachers--United States--History; Women domestics--United States--History; Women government executives--History; Women historians--United States--History; Women in the labor movement--History; Women in the professions--United States--History; Women in politics--United States--History; Women labor union members--United States--History; Women lawyers--United States--History; Women philanthropists--History; Women scientists--United States--History; World War, 1939-1945--Women--United States; World War, 1914-1918--Women--United States; Sophia Smith Collection
Additional Information
Additional Finding Aids Available
Handwritten title list for U.S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau publications (boxes 10-10d) available in Sophia Smith Collection Reading Room.
- SERIES I. GENERAL
  - Bibliographies 1963-82 (Box 1)
  - "Textile Industries: Factory Workers," Women in Industry and Trade, circa 19th century (Box 1a, Folder 1)
  - Women in the workplace, articles and papers 1900, 1974, n.d (Box 1a, Folder 2)
  - Exhibit brochures 1978-81, undated (Box 1a, Folder 3)
  - Conferences 1982 (Box 1a, Folder 4)
  - Articles 1873-81, undated (Box 1a, Folder 5-6)
  - Newspaper clippings 1864-1981, undated (Box 1b, Folder 1-3)
  - U.S. Department of Labor Women's Bureau pamphlets 1-231956-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
  - U.S. Department of Labor Women's Bureau leaflets 1-531943-1983 (Box 2, Folder 8-11)
  - U.S. Department of Labor Women's Bureau women's liberation pamphlets1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - U.S. Department of Labor Women's Bureau women's liberation fact sheets1968-1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - U.S. Department of Labor, Beth Green1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous printed material regarding women workers pamphlets 1950-1980 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous fliers regarding women's labor19718-1975 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Female workers pamphlets, various publishers1932-1952 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Female workers pamphlets, various publishers1964-2000 (Box 2a, Folder 1-6)
  - Books1903 (Box 2a, Folder 7)
  - Lectures and addresses, circa 20th century (Box 2b, Folder 1-2)
  - Subjects
    - Affirmative action 1971-78 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Child labor 1937-79, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
      [see also books on shelf]
    - Consumers 1968-71 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Career goals 1963-75 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Discrimination 1963-74 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Employment Standards Administration (conferences) 1939-72 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Equality 1948-79 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Equal Pay
      - General 1970-79 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Crowe vs. Boston Redevelopment Authority: correspondence, clippings, press releases, and printed materials compiled by co-complainant, Rosalind Pollan 1974 (Box 3a)
    - Job sharing 1975, undated (Box 3b, Folder 1)
    - Low-income women 1970, 1978 (Box 3b, Folder 1a)
    - Married women 1924-62 (Box 3b, Folder 2)
    - Mothers 1970-73 (Box 3b, Folder 3)
    - Minimum wage 1919-62 (Box 3b, Folder 4)
    - Minorities 1979, undated (Box 3b, Folder 5)
    - Protective legislation (conference, Smith College) 1977 (Box 3b, Folder 6)
    - Social Security 1980 (Box 3b, Folder 7)
    - Statistics 1968-79 (Box 3b, Folder 8)
    - Triangle fire 1911): thesis by Hope Rockefeller, 1959 (Box 3c, Folder 1)
    - Volunteer service 1973-79 (Box 3c, Folder 2)
    - Want ads undated (Box 3c, Folder 3)
- SERIES II. COUNTRIES
  - Australia 1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Austria 1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Belgium 1970s, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Canada (Box 4)
    - Pamphlets 1920-67, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Articles and clippings 1918-29, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Women Workers in Multinational Corporations, Linda Lim (Malaysia and Singapore) 1978 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Organization for Economic Co-Operation and Development Conference Report 1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Denmark 1980 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Europe 1928-73 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Finland 1980 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - France 1874-1940, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Germany (Box 4)
    - General 1928-56, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Pamphlets 1919-80, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Internationales Arbeitsamt 1934-35 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - India 1918-29 (Box 4a, Folder 1)
  - International 1980 (Box 4a, Folder 2)
  - Ireland 1980 (Box 4a, Folder 3)
  - Italy 1919-23, 1980, undated (Box 4a, Folder 4)
  - Japan 1920-28, 1980 (Box 4a, Folder 5)
  - Netherlands (Box 4a, Folder 6)
  - New Zealand 1980 (Box 4a, Folder 7)
  - Norway 1980 (Box 4a, Folder 8)
  - Orient (Women in the Orient 1926 (Box 4a, Folder 9)
  - Portugal 1980 (Box 4a, Folder 10)
  - Russia 1942 (Box 4a, Folder 11)
  - Spain 1980 (Box 4a, Folder 12)
  - Sweden 1980 (Box 4a, Folder 13)
  - Switzerland 1980 (Box 4a, Folder 14)
  - Turkey 16-17 Apr 1980 (Box 4a, Folder 15)
  - England (Box 4a)
    - Pamphlets and pictures 1898-1965, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Magazine articles 1862-1931, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Clippings 1917-30 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Factory bills 1926 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Equal Pay Campaign Committee 1944-52 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Comeback: A Guide for the Educated Woman Returning to Work 1964 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Federation of Women Civil Servants 1923-29, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - London Women's Parliament 1941 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Consultative Committee of Women's Organizations, London 1922-27 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Women in Management by Eleanor MacDonald1971-74, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - National Union of Women Workers 1916 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - National Report for the OECD Conference on Employment of Women 1980 (Box 5)
    - Vigilance Association for the Defense of Personal Rights 1926 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Women's Cooperative Guild, Sheffield, England 1919 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Women's Industrial Council 1899-1918 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Women's Protective and Provident League 1874-1918 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - United States (Box 5)
    - Third National Conference of Commissions on the Status of Women, Panel on Labor Standards and Equal Employment Opportunity for Women 29 Jun 1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Great Depression 1926-35 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - States 1938-41, 1979-80 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - California: "Child Labor," by Mrs. Francis Noel 1909 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Colorado 1972, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Connecticut 1962 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Kansas 1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Maryland 1918 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Massachusetts 1901, 1960-78 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Nebraska 1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - New York 1929-77 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Ohio 1978-79 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Utah 1978 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - U.S. Department of Labor (Box 6)
      - Outline of the Industrial Sanitation Code 1923 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Division of Labor Standards 1938-44 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Bureau of Labor Statistics 1941, 1975, 1985-89 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Women's Bureau (Box 6)
        - General publications 1920-80, undated (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
        - Bibliographies 1957-70 (Box 7, Folder 3)
        - States 1946-84 (Box 7a, Folder 1)
        - Subjects (Box 7a)
          - Conferences 1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
          - Counseling 1964-72 (Box 8, Folder 2)
          - Defense 1940-46 (Box 8, Folder 3)
          - Domestic employment 1949-78 (Box 8, Folder 4)
          - Economic Role of Women (conference) 11-13 Sep 1975 (Box 8, Folder 5)
          - Education of women 1963-74 (Box 8, Folder 6)
          - Employment Standards Administration 1973-79 (Box 8, Folder 7)
          - Equal opportunity 1945-75 (Box 8, Folder 8)
          - Equal pay 1949-76 (Box 8, Folder 9)
          - Government service 1949-70 (Box 8, Folder 10)
          - Handicapped 1958 (Box 8, Folder 11)
          - Immigration 1948 (Box 8, Folder 12)
          - Women in industry 1946-74 (Box 8, Folder 13)
          - International documents on status of women 1963 (Box 8, Folder 14)
          - Jury duty 1950-53 (Box 9, Folder 1)
          - Legal status 1950-78 (Box 9, Folder 2)
          - Low income 1977 (Box 9, Folder 3)
          - Mature women 1950-70 (Box 9, Folder 4)
          - Minimum wage 1936-58 (Box 9, Folder 5)
          - Minorities 1948-77 (Box 9, Folder 6)
          - Working mothers 1968-77, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
          - Occupational pamphlets 1951-80 (Box 9, Folder 8)
          - Under-utilization of women workers 1967 (Box 9, Folder 9)
          - Unions 1977-80, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
          - Wartime 1940-44 (Box 9, Folder 11)
          - "The Woman Worker"; "Facts on Women Workers"1938-70 (Box 9, Folder 12)
        - Bulletins [see title list in back of finding aid folder, SSC Reading Room] (Box 9)
          - Nos. 2-64 (1919-28) (Box 10)
          - Nos. 65-146 (1928-33) (Box 10a)
          - Nos. 147-223 1936-40 (Box 10b)
          - Nos. 224-265 1948-50 (Box 10c)
          - Nos. 266-297 1958-75 (Box 10d)
    - Day Care (Box 10d)
      - Bibliographies 1953, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - General 1969-72, undated (Box 11, Folder 2-4)
      - Clippings 1970-73 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - "Free Play": newsletter of Childcare Workers of Connecticut 1975-77, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Magazine articles 1970-73 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Pamphlets 1968-81 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- SERIES III. DOMESTIC SERVICE
  - Bibliography 1938, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "Female Servants and Economic Development"1978 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - "Michigan Occasional Papers in Women's Studies"1978 (Box 12)
  - General 1910-73 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Magazine articles 1928-39 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - National Committee Bulletins 1925-36 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - National Council Reports 1940-42 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Clippings 1928-45, 1973-76 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous reports 1930-39, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Social Security 1939-46 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Trade unions 1920-39, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Wages and working standards 1930-74, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Pamphlets (Box 12)
    - Domestic workers training 1930-39, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - General 1914-43, 1970, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Photographs (Box 13, Folder 3)
- SERIES IV. INDUSTRIAL RELATIONS
  - General (Box 13)
    - Pamphlets 1919-52 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Clippings 1906-33 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Magazine articles 1900-44, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - International Industrial Welfare and Personnel Congress 1925 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - U.S. Senate Finance Committee Report 1894 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Pictures of factory workers 1893-1929, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - International Labor Organization Treaty 1939, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Women's Industrial Conference, Report, Washington, D.C. 1923 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Association of Working Girls' Societies 1890 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - World War I (Box 14)
    - Pamphlets (Box 14)
      - General (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - U.S. Government publications (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - YWCA publications (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Women's Committee, Council of National Defense (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - England (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Photographs of women workers (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - World War II (Box 15)
    - Clippings (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Women's Bureau Bulletins (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Women's Bureau Special Bulletins (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Government publications (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - YWCA publications (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - "War Demands for Trained Personnel"1942, [see books on shelf] (Box 16)
    - College women and war work 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - England 1940-44 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Canada; Germany; New Zealand 1941-43 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Post-War Work 1942-53 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Open Door International (Box 18)
    [see also La Travailleuse Tranquée in Periodicals Collection]
    - Circular letters 1949-68 (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
    - Publications 1929-64, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Conference reports, announcements, etc. 1929-68 (Box 18, Folder 5-10)
    - Open Door Council (British Branch) 1929-1937 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Open Door Council (British Branch of International) 1929-37 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - International Congress of Working Women (Box 18)
    - General (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Reports of 1st Conference 1919 (Box 19, Folder 2-6)
    - Reports of 2nd Conference 1921 (Box 19, Folder 7-8)
    - Reports of 3rd Conference 1923 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- SERIES V. OCCUPATIONS
  - General (Box 19)
    - Women in professions 1908-84 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Committee Investigating Professional Opportunities 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Catalyst 1964-82 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Institute of Women's Professional Relations 1938-44 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - A Woman's Work; an annual publication on careers of women 1967 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous occupations: clippings, articles, and pamphlets 1899-1976 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Professional Women's Caucus 1970-74 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Accounting 1977 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Advertising 1924-77 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Agriculture (Box 20)
    - Clippings 1912-72 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Magazine articles 1917-77 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Pamphlets 1915-30, 1975-77 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Farm and Garden Association, New England Branch 1930 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Stockbridge School of Agriculture 1958 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Women's Agricultural Times 1904 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Farm and Garden Apr-Aug 1960 (Box 21)
  - Aquanautics 1970 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Archaeology (Box 21)
    - General 1923-71, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Amelia B. Edwards 1889-90 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Architecture 1923, 1967-75 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Archivists 1973-83 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Astrology (incl. Evangeline Adams) 1925 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Athletes 1972-76 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Auctioneers 1923, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Auto industry 1974 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Auto mechanics 1929, 1977, undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Autograph dealers (Mary Benjamin) 1959 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Automobile racing 1973 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Banking (Box 21)
    - Photographs circa 1880 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - General 1920-33, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Clippings (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Genevieve Gildersleeve 1951-59 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Blue collar workers 1973-79 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Bookbinders 1901-30 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Business (Box 22)
    - Bibliography: The Woman Manager in the U.S. 1981 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Executives 1927-28, 1959-82 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      [see also RECENT ADDITIONS, box 44a]
    - Clippings 1909-79 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Rebecca Lukens 1940, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Henrietta Howland Robinson Green 1915-16, 1929 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Circus 1854-61, 1970-71 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Clerical 1973-80 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Communication 1931-77 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Computers 1970 (Box 22a, Folder 1)
  - Construction (Box 22a)
    - General 1921-77 (Box 22a, Folder 2)
    - All Craft Center 1980-82 (Box 22a, Folder 3)
  - Cooking 1921-24 (Box 22a, Folder 4)
  - Counselors: Charlotte M. Reardon 1943-44 (Box 22a, Folder 5)
  - CPAs: The Woman CPA by Eunice E. Stockman 1971 (Box 22a, Folder 6)
  - Dentistry 1971-79 (Box 22a, Folder 7)
  - Detectives 1971-72 (Box 22a, Folder 8)
  - Dockworkers 1971, 1979 (Box 22a, Folder 9)
  - Ecologists 1969-70 (Box 22a, Folder 10)
  - Engineers (Box 22a)
    - General 1924-75 (Box 22a, Folder 11)
    - Lillian Moller Gilbreth 1930-73 (Box 22a, Folder 12)
  - Entrepreneurs 1972-76 (Box 22a, Folder 13)
  - Firefighters 1973-79, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Flight attendants 1972-76 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Forestry 1923-81 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Fur trading: Sally Ainse, Fur Trader by Fred Hamil 1939 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Geographers (Box 23)
    - General 1871-1985 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Dorothy May Anderson 1950 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - The Society of Women Geographers 1945-84 (Box 23)
  - Home economics 1924-80 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Housing 1901-64 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Insurance 1921, 1963-71 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Inventors 1874-1972 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Jewelry 1930, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Journalism (Box 24)
    - General 1892-1978 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Asbury, Edith Evans (Box 24, Folder 4a)
    - Nellie Bly: "Around the World with Nellie Bly" game circa 1890, [see Oversized materials] (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Erma Bombeck 1971 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Jane Croly 1882, 1893, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Dorothea Dix undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Rheta Childe Dorr undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Gertrude Gordon 1927 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Sarah Josepha Hale 1923-33 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Caroline Huling undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Freda Kirchwey 1923, 1944-46 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Anne O'Hare McCormick 1939 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Adela Rogers St. Johns 1970 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Helen Thomas: photographs 1967 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Dorothy Thompson (Box 24)
      - General 1938-50 (Box 24, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence with agent 1960-64 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Gertrude Wickham 1965 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Landscaping 1972 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Lecturers (Box 24)
    - General 1900-39 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Anna E. Dickinson 1865-1952, undated (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Librarians 1886-1974 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Logging and timber industry 1979-81 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Management consultants 1969-74 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Media 1970-82 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Merchant Marines 1978, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Miners 1911-79 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Models 1969 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Movers 1923, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper editors (Jane Grey Swisshelm) 1967, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Office workers, circa 1900 1920-82 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Older women workers 1924-30, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Park rangers 1976-77 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Pharmacists 1927-73 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Philatelists 1953 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Photographers (Box 25)
    - General 1910-72 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Diane Arbus 1973 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Physics 1962 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Pilots 1958 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Plebiscites (Sarah Wambaugh) 1946, undated (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Plumbers 1910-71 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Police officers (Box 25)
    - England 1919-74 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - International Association of Policewomen 1925-26 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - United States 1919-77 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Printers 1923-77 (Box 25a, Folder 1)
  - Prison guards 1974 (Box 25a, Folder 2)
  - Publishers 1925-84 (Box 25a, Folder 3)
  - Psychology 1931-79, undated (Box 25a, Folder 4)
  - Radio 1925-78 (Box 25a, Folder 5)
  - Railroading 1919-30 (Box 25a, Folder 6)
  - Real estate 1921-32 (Box 25a, Folder 7)
  - Recording studios 1975 (Box 25a, Folder 8)
  - Restaurateurs 1977 (Box 25a, Folder 9)
  - Retail trade 1917-62 (Box 25a, Folder 10)
  - Sociologists 1970-71 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Stockbrokers 1958, 1977, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Taxi drivers 1923 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Teachers 1967-77 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Textile Workers (Box 26)
  - Trades 1980 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Travel 1856, 1962, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Waitressing 1907, 1975-76 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Welders undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
- SERIES VI. ACADEMIC WOMEN
  - Fields of study 1970-77, undated (Box 26)
    - Administration (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - American Women and American Studies by Betty E. Chmaj 1971 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Art (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Legal education (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Mathematics (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Museums (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Psychology (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Science (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Sociology (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Historians (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 27a, Folder 1)
    - American Historical Association (Box 27a, Folder 2)